I see a lot of people figure it out to
我看到很多人弄明白到
come early so good for you so if you
早来对你那么好，所以如果你
recall my name is Randy Bryant and I'm
还记得我的名字是 兰迪·布赖恩特和我
Co instructor of this course along with
这当然伴随 着联合教练
Dave O'Halloran and for the next couple
达沃·奥哈洛兰并为接下来的几个
lectures the first part of this course
讲课 本课程的第一部分
really will be talking about sort of
真的会被谈论 的排序
data representations in particular how
尤其是如何的数据表示
numbers are represented in different
号通常是 在不同的 表示
forms and some of the properties and you
形式和一些属性 和你
saw that when I talked last week I
看到，当我跟我上周
showed you things like you can multiply
显示你喜欢的东西，你可以 乘
some numbers together that are positive
一些数字加在一起是积极的
and get negative result so what we want
并得到阴性 结果，我们想让我们什么
to understand is what is the bit level
要了解是什么，是位水平
representation of numbers and how does
数字的表示 和如何做
that affect some of the properties you
影响某些属性你
have when you operate them on and
当你在操作它们 具有 和
especially looking at the corner cases
尤其是看着角落里的情况
when things overflow or we sort of don't
当事情溢出或我们有点 不
do what you might expect them to do so
你可以期望他们这样做
we'll start off with very basic stuff of
我们将用非常基本的东西开始
how numbers are represented especially
数字是如何特别代表
integer valued numbers are represented
整数值的数字被表示
in bits so I think you've pretty well
在位，这样我觉得你不错
figured out in this world that the whole
在这个世界上想通了，整个
digital world is sort of based on on
数字世界排序的基础上
binary values and that wasn't always the
二进制值而不是总是
case I mean since humans have ten
情况下， 我的意思是，因为人类有 十个
fingers and ten toes a lot of the world
手指和十个脚趾很多 世界
was based on the decimal system and it
基于十进制和它
was really only and in fact the first
其实只和事实上的第一
electronic computer the ENIAC built in
电子计算机ENIAC的在建
University of Pennsylvania basically
宾夕法尼亚大学基本上
encoded did all of its arithmetic using
编码的所有 运算用做
base ten they had 10 vacuum tubes per
基座 10 他们有 10个真空管每
digit they wanted to represent so they
数字， 他们希望 代表，使他们
basically turned on or off those tubes
基本上开启或关闭的那些管
to represent which of the 10 possible
来 表示其10 个可能 的
digits you could want and it really
数字你能想到它真的
didn't come to people until later than
没来的人，直到比晚
that so that's 1948 that they really
这让在1948年，他们真的
should just think about base tube for
应该想想 为 基 管
everything
一切
and the reason why bits are great is in
为什么是位伟大的原因是
the digital world you can sort of take
你可以排序的利用 数字世界
what otherwise an analog signal and
否则什么模拟 信号
quantify it
它量化
and just say I'm going to say that one
而只是说我会说一
range of values would say it's a low
值的范围会说这是一个低
voltage I'm going to call that a zero
电压 我要调用一个零
and a high range of values I'm going to
和高值范围我要去
call it a one and if there's noise or
说它是一个，如果有噪音或
imperfections in the circuit or
在电路中的缺陷或
anything's going on as long as that
只要东西是怎么回事作为
doesn't exceed these bit these
不超过上述这些位
thresholds you've set up then you'll get
阈值，你已经建立了，那么你会得到
a nice clean signal out of it and that's
一个干净的信号出来的 ， 这就是
the main advantage of digital processing
数字处理的主要优点
over analog processing and so that sort
在模拟处理，并且使得排序
of at the core why everything we do and
为核心，为什么我们所做的一切 和
especially for storing information it
特别是用于存储信息的其
turns out it's much easier to store one
原来，这是很容易来存储一个
bit of information or a digital value
的信息或数字值位
than it is to store an analog value and
比它是存储模拟值与
sorry this kind of slides went a little
抱歉，这种幻灯片就稍
crazy on animation so the point is that
疯狂的动漫这样的一点是，
we represent all the numbers in a
我们代表的所有号码
computer as sets of bits and I think you
计算机组位， 我想你
generally understand that fairly well
一般理解得相当好
and so of course the familiar binary
所以当然熟悉的二进制
representation of integers which we'll
整数表示我们将
go over today just uses a bit position
去了今天刚刚使用位位置
for each power of two we can also
对于每两个力量，我们也可以
represent values that are fractional and
表示是分数值和
we'll talk about that a week from today
我们将谈论， 从今天一个星期
when we do a floating-point numbers
当我们做一个浮点数
where what you do is to the right of the
在那里，你做的是对 的 权
binary point so this is no longer a
二进制点 因此这不再是一个
decimal point it's a binary point and so
小数点这是一个二进制点等
something to the left of that would have
东西的，左将有
a weight one two to the zero and the
一重量的一种两到零 和
next one over would have weight to the
下一个过将不得不重来的
one but what you do is is you go to the
之一，但你要做的就是为你去
right that adds weight to the minus one
正确的重量增加至减一
to the minus two in other words this is
在换句话说 ，负二 ，这是
1 this is 2 this is one half and this is
1，这是2，这是一个半，这 是
1/4 so we can represent just like you do
1/4，所以我们可以代表就像你做
the decimal representation of fractions
级分的十进制表示
we can do the binary representation of
我们可以做的二进制表示
fractions so that's the core of
分数所以这是核心
floating-point number of representations
表示的浮点数
and so
所以
it gets very annoying if you have say 32
如果你说32它变得很烦人
or even 64-bit numbers to be writing the
甚至是64位数字被写入
strings of ones and zeros out and so
者的字符串和零出等
what we use and what's become largely
我们用什么样的，什么是成为主要
the the most common is to group
在最常见的是组
collections of four bits at a time into
每次 向 四位集合
and then represent that in base 16 or
然后表示在基部16或
what's known as hexadecimal
什么作为 十六进制
representation using the letters A
使用字母A表示
through F as values 10 through 15 and
到F为值10至15和
you'll spend a lot of time staring at
你会花很多时间盯着
exa decimal numbers this year and you'll
今年 ，你会 EXA小数
get pretty good at being able to look at
在获得能看还不错
a hex number just write it out in binary
一个十六进制数只写出来的二进制
the way I do it just to tell you is I
我这样做 只是为了告诉你 的方式 是我
mean I've got the values from 0 to 9
意思是我从 0到 9得了值
wired down pretty well and then I keep
有线下得很好，然后我不断
track of a few special cases 1 0 1 0
轨道的少数特殊情况 1 0 1 0
it's a 1 1 0 0 is C and 1 1 1 1 F and
它是一个1 1 0 0 是 C和1 1 1 1 F和
for B D and E I kind of interpolate
对于BD和EI样的插值
between those so if you want to develop
这些所以如果你想 开发之间
that skill that's the way you can do it
这个 技能那是你能做到这一点的方式
you're looking for Jesse my connector
你要找 的杰西我的连接器
that was an HDMI - what no I don't think
这是一个HDMI -什么不，我不认为
there's any connector here you know No
有任何连接器在这里 ，你知道不
so that's something you're going to end
所以这件事情你要结束
up wanting to be able to do so in C we
达希望能够 用C，我们这样做
don't in most
不要在最
declarations you don't actually are told
你实际上并不声明说
exactly how many bytes abide is eight
到底有多少 字节的 遵守是 八
bits each data value is represented as
位的每个数据值被表示为
and that's partly C was designed
而这部分下设计
actually back when microprocessors only
实际上只回来时，微处理器
had 16-bit words it was actually before
有16位字，它实际上是前
micro processors so 16-bit words were a
微处理器所以16位字是个
fairly standard thing and over time
相当标准的事情，随着时间的推移
that's expanded from 16 to 32 to now 64
这是一个从16 至32扩展到64现在
and so C rather than a sort of an
和所以C，而不是一种的
advanced saying here is how many bytes
先进的说这里是多少字节
every value will have has these slightly
每个值将有小幅这些
ambiguous terms that vary actually from
模糊的术语，从实际上改变
one machine to the next and if you're a
一台机器到下一个 ，如果你是一个
very careful C programmer you have to
你必须非常小心，C程序员
anticipate that zone but what won't deal
预计该区域，但什么是最不会处理
with is x86 64 is the class of machines
与是86 64是级的机器的
will be working with exclusively this
将与此独家合作
term and so you can see that when you
长期， 所以你可以看到，当你
declare something to be a care sometimes
声明的东西要照顾，有时
people call it a char that the one byte
人们把它叫做一个字符 是一个 字节
value a short is 16 by a bit an INT is
值的短是由16位的 INT 是
32 and if you want to get all 64 bits
32， 如果你想获得的所有64 位
you have to declare it to be along and
您必须声明它是沿着与
then again there's two different
然后再有两个不同
Precision's of floating-point there's
精密的浮点有
four byte or 32-bit floating point
四个字节或32位的浮点
numbers and 64 bits there's also a
数位和64位也有一个
slightly obscure holdover from ancient
从古代略微晦涩缓缴
days of of floating point where there's
天浮点那里的的
a special representation in Intel
在英特尔的特别代表
machines that uses a 10 bite or 80 bit
使用一个10 咬合或80位机器
representation and when you use that on
表示， 当你使用上
a 64-bit machine they sort of waste an
一个64位的机器，他们那种 浪费的
extra six bit bytes out of that so that
额外的六位字节出的是 使
everything is aligned in sixteen byte
一切都在十六字节对齐
increments the other thing and this is
增加其他的事情， 这 是
an important feature is any address is
一个重要的特点是任何地址
defined
定义
to be the sort of the word size of the
要排序的字大小
machine when they say it's a 64-bit
当他们说机器是64位
machine what they really mean is that
机他们真正的意思是，
the addresses are 64 bit values or 8
所述地址是 64个值或 8
byte values and that's different for
字节值，这对不同
example if you use a older machine a 32
例如 ，如果您 使用的是旧机器32
bit machine those will only be 32-bit
位 机那些将仅32位
addresses so the basis and I imagine
地址，使依据和我想象
you've had this at some point of how do
你在怎么做某些时候有这个
we then think about bits is based on
我们再想想 基于位
boolean algebra which is actually comes
布尔代数这实际上是来自
from the 1890s that a guy named George
从一个人叫乔治的19世纪90年代
Boole who recognized it's sort of
布尔谁认识这有点
relation between what we'd call bits but
之间我们会打电话位，但关系
they weren't called bits beck 1001 and
他们不叫位 使唤1001
logic are basically truth values in
逻辑是在基本上真值
logic I'm thinking of an algebra sort of
逻辑我 想代数的排序
a structured set of operations you could
操作的结构化组你可以
apply that would capture some of the
应用会捕捉一些的
concepts that people assume is in logic
人们假设的概念是 在逻辑
so for example if we think of 1 being
因此，例如，如果我们认为1所存在 的
true and 0 being false then the end
真和0 是假，则端
operation is true if both of the inputs
操作为真，如果两者的 输入端
both of the arguments are true so we get
双方 的论据是真实的，所以我们得到
this chart here and similarly the or
这里这张图，类似的或
operation is true if either input is
如果任一输入 为 操作为真
true or 1 the not is just to flip the
真或1的 不只是 翻转
bit and then the exclusive-or is what
位，然后异或 什么
you get when you say it's one or the
你当你说这是一个或
other but not both and so it has this
其他 但不能 两者都 ，所以它有这个
representation so just as a bit of
表示，以便就如同一 点点
history it was a master's degree student
历史上，这是 一个硕士 生
at MIT named Claude Shannon who had
在麻省理工学院的名为克劳德·香农谁了
taken a course in logic as an
在逻辑截取的路线作为
undergraduate at University of Michigan
本科在密歇根大学
and he was the one who made the
他是谁提出的一个
connection between thinking about this
想着这之间的连接
this what was at the time very obscure
这是什么的时候非常晦涩
branch of something a rather of logic
的东西，而逻辑的分支
and applying it to digital systems back
并把它应用到数字系统回
in an era when they actually built these
在这样一个时代，当他们实际上是建立这些
things out of electromechanical
东西出来机电的
and so his master's thesis is probably
所以他的硕士论文是可能
the most impactful master's thesis in
最有影响力的硕士论文中
the history of humankind
人类 历史
and you always wonder well what did they
而你总是不知道还有什么做他们
do before that then you know how do they
在此之前，你就会知道他们怎么
even think about these things so anyways
即使考虑这些事情，所以不管怎么说
the idea of applying this algebra then
应用此代数随后的想法
to bits is not something that should
对位是不是应该
have been true since the world began
因为 世界开始 是真实的
it's something that's a relatively
它的东西，这是一个相对
modern concept now what's an important
现代概念现在什么是重要的
thing that might be less obvious is we
这可能 是不太 明显的是我们
can also do these over words we can do
也可以做这些了的话，我们可以做
these boolean operations where we apply
在这里我们将这些布尔运算
them on each successive bit in that word
他们对 这个词 每个连续的位
and these symbols we use the ampersand
而这些符号，我们使用的符号
vertical bar carrot and tilde are
竖条胡萝卜和波浪线被
actually the ones that see uses to
实际上是看 使用的那些
represent these operations and so again
代表这些操作等再次
if we look at here the one is only if
如果我们 看看这里的一个只有当
both of the values of 1 and the of for
二者 的1 的值的 和的对
the or for the and for the wants or if
在或为，为想要或者如果
either of number 1 the exclusive or if 1
任一数目的1的异或，如果 1
is 1 and the other is 0 until it is just
为1，其他 是 0，直到它只是
invert the bits of it so again we will
如此反复颠倒它的位，我们将
spend a lot of time making use of the
花费了大量的时间利用的
fact that in see and this is one of the
事实上，在看到 这是 一
features of C that people like is that
的C功能，人们喜欢 的 是 ，
you can do these sort of very low level
你可以做这些种类非常低的水平
of bitna manipulations directly in the
直接bitna操作在的
language and this actually turns out to
语言这实际上都是
be useful in practice and it's sort of
在实践中 ，它的排序
implicit of a way of representing sets
隐含的代表集的方式
of values so this example is a imagine
值所以 这个例子是一个想象
we want to represent sets where the
我们要代表集合，其中的
elements of the set are numbers ranging
该组元件是数为
between 0 & 7 so one bite is enough to
0和7之间，以便一咬足以
capture 8 cases and we'll just if we
捕捉 8例，我们只是如果我们
number the bits and we number them from
的比特数，我们从它们编号
right to left so this is bit zero so
从右到左，所以这是位零，因此
that would represent whether or not the
这将是与否
value 0 is an element of the set and
值0 是 集合 的一个元素 和
similarly here you'll see 0 1 2
同样在这里你会看到0 1 2
three so we're saying that bit three
3次，以我们 的 意思是说 位三所
being one here means three is an element
是一个在这里是指三是一个元件
of the set and so forth and the so the
设定等，并且在这样的
idea is then the end operation becomes
想法是，则结束操作变得
like set intersection the or operation
等设定的交叉点处的操作或
becomes like set Union and the X
变得像集合联盟和 X
exclusive or operation is what's called
异或运算是所谓
symmetric difference and so these are
对称差，因此这些是
actually and tilde is like set
其实和波浪就像是集
complement so these are actually very
补充 所以这实际上是非常
common for example there's a operations
常见的例子有一个操作
you'll learn later when we look at a
以后你会知道什么时候我们来看 一个
file i/o about i/o that you can track I
文件I / O有关I / O，你可以跟踪 我
want to know which set of possible
想知道哪些设置的可能
inputs to the system think of different
输入到系统思考的不同
network connections have an input ready
网络连接 有一个输入就绪
for me to read and there is a data
对我来说，阅读和有一个数据
structure that it's sort of hidden away
结构这有点 藏起来
among some seeing library calls but it
看到一些库调用，但中
basically is using exactly this
基本上使用的正是 这种
representation about a thousand a bits
代表大约有一千一位
worth of information to represent these
信息的价值来表示这些
sets and do manipulation on those sets
设置并做那些操纵套
so this is a very common and why do we
所以这是一个非常常见的 ，为什么 我们
use representation of sets in computer
使用的集计算机表示
science so as I mentioned those are
科学使我提到的那些
available directly and see the ampersand
直接可用 ，看到了符号
vertical bar tilde and caret one thing
竖条波浪和尖 一件事
that's really really important and that
这是真的 真的很重要，
programmers screw it up all the time
程序员搞砸了所有的 时间
beginning programmers a lot and even
初级程序员很多，甚至
experienced programmers from time to
有经验的程序员，从时间
time is to mix up the single ampersand
时间是混合了单个号
in the double ampersand or the single
在双符号或单
vertical bar in the double vertical bar
在双竖线竖线
and the tilde versus the exclamation
和波浪线与感叹号
mark which is often pronounced bang so
标记，是常常发音爆炸等等
and the reason so obviously there's sort
而之所以这么明显有排序
of a syntactic similarity there's
句法相似的还有
actually somewhat of a semantic relation
其实有些语义关系
to that this is another kind of
对，这是另一种
another kind of or and another kind of
另一种或与另一种
not but if you mix and match these
没有，但如果你混搭这些
you're certainly going to have problems
你一定要去有问题
so the double bar ones aren't thinking
因此，双杆 的人都没有想到
about bitwise operations through
通过对位操作
thinking about something that's either
思考的东西 ，要么
true or false periods and in that
在真或假期间和
representation the number zero is the
表示数字零是
thing that faults and anything else any
事情在断层和别的任何
other bit pattern is considered to be
其他的位模式被认为是
true and so it the other feature that
真实，所以 它的其他功能，
the double bonds give you is what's
双键给你的是什么
called early termination so in
所谓提前终止所以在
particular if we do some examples on the
特别是如果我们做 的 一些例子
some hex pattern for one so this is a a
对于一个十六进制的一些模式，所以这是AA
not a zero and so that's considered true
不是零，因此人们心目中 真正的
in this interpretation and so the the
在这种解释等等的
bang of that the not of that is zero and
那的不是爆炸就是零和
similarly if you have zero the not event
同样，如果你有零不是事件
is one and if you apply bang to a number
是一个，如果你申请的一声多项
twice you'll get back a one unless it
两次你会 得到一个除非它
was zero and then similarly these
是零，然后 这些 类似
patterns here are the reason why this
这里模式是之所以这样
returns one is because it's considered
返回一个是因为它被认为是
two cases that are true so it's not
2箱子所以它不是属实
doing bitwise operations it's just
做位运算，它只是
trying to create true and false
努力创造真假
it's interpreting argument speeds or
它的解释说法速度或
true or false and returning either true
真或假 ，返回值为true
or false
还是假的
but when it returns true it returns one
但是，当它返回true，则返回一个
and not whatever number you happen to
而不是你碰巧的任何数字
give it so obviously this is a very
给它所以显然这是一个非常
different operations than you have with
不同的操作比你有
the single versions of those and but
单一版本的和的，但
it's easy just because you mentally slip
这很容易只是因为你精神上滑
or because you type something wrong to
或者是因为你输入的东西错了
do the wrong time but in particularly
做错误的时间，但在特别
this early termination is something that
这种提前终止是一件
of course people use a lot if you want
当然 ，如果你 想 用 的人 很多
to make sure that you're not accessing a
确保你没有访问
null pointer you can test whether that's
空指针，你可以测试是否这是
a null pointer first before accessing it
一个空指针第一访问它之前
and this if this is zero
这如果是 零
No then it will do the the dereferencing
没有那么它会做的提领
of null so it's a fairly useful feature
空的所以这是一个非常有用的功能
as well so anyways just that's an aside
还有这样反正只是 这是一个搁置
at this level we're mostly looking at
在这个 层面我们主要是看
bits but just as a programming note
位，但只是作为一种编程注意事项
don't mix these up the other class of
不要混淆这些了其他类 的
operations will make use of a lot are
操作将使用大量的是
shifting which again is not something
移动这又是不是
that you normally sort of as beginning
您通常排序为 开端
programmers think about too much and if
程序员想太多，如果
there's a curious feature that a left
有一个奇怪的特点， 一个左
shifts are always the same but there's
转变始终是相同的，但有
two different flavors of right shift and
向右移位的两种不同的口味 和
we'll see in a little bit later why
我们会在一点点 后，为什么看
there's two different flavors of right
有右两个不同的口味
shift but um the idea then of shifting
调整，但恩的想法，然后转移的
is that you have some argument X and you
是，你有一些参数X和你
want to shift it some number of
要转变它的一些数
positions either to the left or to the
位置要么 向左或向
right given by Y and so when you shift
由Y权给予，所以当你转移
left you just fill in whatever value
离开你只需填写任何值
there was so you pick up the I'm
有那么你拿起我
shifting by three so I'll take the lower
三移，所以我会采取较低
order five bits move them over three
五 阶 位移动他们在三年
positions and then fill in with a zero
位置，然后填以零
and whatever was in the upper positions
也不论是在上部位置
of that original word they just sort of
即原词 ， 他们只是有点
disappear into the of into nowhere
消失在进入无处
similarly if I do a right shift I kicked
同样的，如果我做一个右移我踢
the upper six bits I move them over to
上六位我将它们移动到
positions and I fill in with zeros so
职位和我填用零如此
that's a logical shift and that's well
这是一个 合乎逻辑的转变 ，这是很好
it's logical um there's another flavor
它的逻辑UM有另一番风味
called the arithmetic shift which it
称为算术移位，它
differs in that the rule for what bits
的 区别在于 什么位规则
you fill in with are not based on the
您填写在并非基于该
are not zeros necessarily but it's
不为零必然，但它
whatever the most significant bit was in
无论是最显著位是
the original value so it doesn't matter
原来的值，因此也无所谓
here because the most significant bit
这里因为最显著位
was zero but you'll see in the case here
是零，但 你会在这里的情况看
of where the leading bit was a one that
哪里的前导位是一个
when I shift it to the right arithmetic
当我把它转移到右边 算术
we I'll fill it in with once and that'll
我们，我会在补了一次，那会
make sense more
意义更
when we understand how negative numbers
当我们了解负数
get represented in a machine and that's
获得代表在一台机器，这就是
the purpose of it and why it's called
它的目的和为什么它被称为
arithmetic oh the other thing that is
算术噢， 那是另一件事
kind of confusing to people is what what
那种混乱的人是什么什么
should happen if you say I want to shift
如果你说我想转移应该发生
an 8-bit number eight positions to the
一个8位的数 八个位置到
left and X is a single byte what do you
左，X是单字节你是什么
think you should get zero that would be
想你应该得到零，这将是
a pretty logical thing you kind of shift
你有种 转变的一个非常顺理成章的事情
all those bits out you fill them with
所有这些位了你，补之 以
zeros on most machines you'll get
你会得到大多数机器零
whatever X was
无论是X
because what it will do is it will
因为它会做的是它会
compute this number mod eight and the
计算这个号模八将
reason that happens is if you think
原因发生 的，如果你认为
about it it's looking at just the low
它它看着眼前的低
order three bits of the shift amount and
订购的移位量的三个比特和
ignoring all the rest so that's
忽略所有的休息 ， 这样 的
effectively like module eight so that's
有效像模块 8所以这
just a warning I and some machines that
只是一个警告， 我和一些机器，
does what you just thought it should and
做什么，你只是觉得 它应该和
other machines that does this and so
其他机器，这是否等
there's no no guarantee and see that it
有没有不能保证，并认为它
will be one way or the other
将一个或 其他 方式
same with if you try to shift left by a
用同样如果您推诿由左
negative number that might be logically
负数， 可能 是逻辑
well I guess you really want to shift
嗯，我想你真的想转移
right then but that usually doesn't work
那么好吧，但通常不工作
either so now let's talk about number
要么所以 现在让我们来谈谈号
representation and this instead of a
表示和本，而不是一个
very core its idea that you have to
非常核心 的想法，你必须
really have wired in you and I'm going
真的有线在你，我 要去
to illustrate it with some examples
用一些例子 来说明 它
so the these two equations then are
所以这两个方程是随后
everything that we'll talk about sort of
我们将谈论那种一切
stems from them so one is if you have an
从他们茎所以一个是如果你有 一个
unsigned number then basically it keeps
无符号数则基本保持它
jumping on you if you have an unsigned
跳跃在你，如果你有一个无符号
number then this is just the the
然后数这仅仅是在
conversion then BTU means from bit sum a
转换然后BTU从比特 之和的 装置
bit level representation to an unsigned
位电平表示为无符号的
number of some bit pattern
某些位模式的数
it just says we'll just add up the sum
它只是说，我们只加起来的总和
of the weighted bits where each bit is
加权位，其中每一个比特是
weighted by a power of two and the only
由二的 幂 和 唯一 的加权
difference when we look at two's
当我们看两个的区别
complement which is a way to represent
补充这是代表一种方式
both negative and positive numbers is
正反两方面的 数字是
we'll consider the most significant bit
我们认为最显著位
to be what's called the time bit so it
是什么所谓的时间位，所以它
will have a negative value so let me
将有一个负值 ，所以让我
just illustrate this with I'll use some
只是说明这一点与我将用 一些
running examples and we'll just use 5
运行的例子，我们将只使用 5
min umbers just as a way it really helps
分umbers只是作为一种方式它确实有助于
often if you're trying to understand
通常，如果你想了解
this stuff to do it for some smaller
这个东西做了一些小的
cases so if we think about bit positions
这样的情况下，如果我们想一想位位置
zero through four then those represent
零通过四个那么这些表示
of different powers of two ways of as
的是 两种方式的不同权力
I've shown and so now if we take some
我已经展示了，因此现在如果我们 采取一些
bit of pattern like so so that's what
格局有点像那么 那么这就是
I'll call X and I want to convert that
我会打电话给X，我想 那 转换
to an unsigned number I will just
一个无符号数我将只
combine eight plus four plus one and
结合八加 四加一和
I'll get 13 all right so that's all that
我会得到13行，这样的一切，
equation says the left-hand equation
方程说， 左手方程
just take the positions that are ones
只是采取是那些位置
use the corresponding power of two and
使用 两种 相应的 功率 和
you're done and similarly if I have a
你就大功告成了，同样，如果我有一个
number where there's a leading bit
数，其中有前位
it will be 16 plus 4 plus 2 so that will
这将是16加4加2 使得 将
be 22 and so that's the unsigned case
是22所以这是未签名的情况下，
and the sign case is the same idea
和符号的情况是一样的 想法
except that most significant debt has a
除了最显著的债务有
negative value so it will still this is
负值所以它仍将 这是
I and our weights will be 1/2 for a but
我和我们的权重将是 1/2的，但
this one I will be minus 16 so that's
这一次，我会在零下16所以这
what the equation on the right is saying
什么右侧的方程说
this bit now we're going to change it
这一点，现在我们要改变 它
from being a negative number to a
从一个负数 到
positive so obviously if I have this is
正如此明显，如果我有这
my bit pattern it's going to be the same
我的位模式这将 是相同的
because the other bits stayed at the
因为其他位住在
same so let's do it for this case of 1 0
同样让我们做 的这种情况下 1 0
1 1 0 so that will be minus 16 plus 4
1 1 0，使得 将负16 加上4
plus 2 so that equal minus 10 all right
加上2使等于10减去没事
so you see in this case we have the same
所以你在这种情况下，看到我们有 相同的
bit pattern it's just if we interpret it
位模式，它只是，如果我们把它解释
you know how we think about what number
你知道我们是怎么想的什么号码
this represents then in one case it's a
这代表则在一个情况下，它是一个
positive number 22 and in another case
正 数22 和 在另一种情况下
it's a negative number minus 10 and
这是一个负数减10
that's what these equations do say
这是这些方程就怎么说
and so the most significant bit is
所以最显著位
sometimes called the sign bit because if
有时也被称为符号位，因为如果
it's a one the number is going to be
这是一个数 将 是
negative so let's say to think about
负 让我们说去思考
what extreme what are the sort of
什么极端的是什么之类的
extreme ranges of numbers we can get
数字，我们可以得到的极端范围
with these two different representations
与这两个不同的 表示
[Applause]
[掌声]
so obviously if these are all zeros my
所以很明显，如果这些都是 我的 零
number is going to equal zero and if
数字是要 等于零 ，如果
it's all one
这一切都一个
it'll be 16 plus 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1
这将是16加8加 4加2加 1
will be 31 and over here for the two's
将两个31个，并在这里
complement the smallest number well the
补充最小号 井
largest number will actually be let me
人数最多的实际上将让我
do it this way actually the most
做到这一点其实 是最 这样
negative number so the smallest number
负数因此 ，最小数
and the strictest sense of the word
而这个词的严格意义上的
is this it's minus 16 you can argue this
这是零下16，你可以 说这
by the way that this is the only bit
由这是唯一位的方式
that has a negative weight all the other
具有负重量所有 其他
ones have positive one so certainly one
那些有积极 的 肯定 这样 一个
and all the rest being zeros is going to
和所有其余为零点将要
be the smallest number consider away the
是最小号考虑走
largest number you can represent will be
你可以代表会 人数最多
8 plus 4 plus 2 plus 1 which is 15
8加4 加2加 1，其为15
and so we call this number you max and
所以我们称之为这个号码你max和
we call this number t max and we call
我们称这个数字t max和我们所说的
this number 2 min so there's a few
这个数字2分钟，以有几
things to observe about these numbers
事情要 观察这些 数字
all that remember this is a 5 bit word
所有记住这是一个 5位字
size right so you'll see that 31 is
大小合适的，所以你会看到，31
pretty close to 32 right in fact it's 2
非常接近32权实际上它是2
to the fifth minus 1 and in general if
第五负1和一般如果
it's a fight and that's for a 5 bit word
这是一个斗争，这对一个5位字
size so you would say in general it will
大小所以你会在一般的说， 这将
have value 2 to the W if I have a W bit
有值2到W，如果我有一个W位
number minus 1 and that's what this
数减1，这也正是这
shows and similarly over here this is 2
显示，同样在 这里 ，这是2
to the minus 2 to the 4th and so we'd
到零下2 到第4， 所以我们会
say in general that will be minus 2 to
概括地说，这将是零下2〜
the W if it's the W bit number minus 1
在W如果是W位数减1
but all these make sense by the way
但所有这些有意义的方式
you'll notice one other feature is
你会发现一个另一个 特点是
a whole string of one like this if you
一个 整串 像这样的，如果你
sum up those digits 8 plus 4 plus 2 plus
综上所述这些数字8加4加2 加
1 will be 1 less than the next bit
1 会 比下位少 1
position up and you can think about that
位置了，你可以考虑一下
if you were to count this number if you
如果你要算，如果你这个号码
were to increment this number by 1 you'd
经1递增此号码 ，你会
get 1 1 is 0 carry 1 and so forth and
得到1 1 0进位1 等，并
you'd carry that value up to this
你会携带价值高达该
position so these various ways you can
位置，使 这些不同的方法，你可以
think about that and then similarly this
想想 ，然后类似这种
number is 2 to the 4th minus 1 and so
数为2〜4号减1，因此
that's equal to 2 to the W minus 1 minus
这等于2到W减1负
1 as is shown here so you know there's a
1为显示在这里，所以你知道有一个
lot of the book goes through formulas
很多书都经过公式
and done starvation's
并做了饥饿的
but if you just think about it in these
但如果你只是想想而已 ，这些
smaller scale ways the intuition is
规模较小的方式直觉
pretty easy to get and don't get lost in
很容易得到，不要迷失 在
in formulas when really at the gut level
在公式时确实在肠道 水平
it's a fairly straightforward sort of
这是一个相当简单的排序
ideas well if you ever see some
想法很好，如果你曾经看到一些
confusions and you confused try out some
困惑和迷茫，你尝试了一些
small examples and see what they're
小例子，看看他们在做什么
saying
话
another interesting number in the world
在世界上的另一个有趣的数字
of two's complement is what happens when
补的是发生在什么
you have all ones in your bit pattern
你有 你的位模式 的所有的人
and that will have 8 minus 16 plus 8
并且，将有 8零下16加8
plus 4 plus 2 plus 1 and that will equal
加4加2加 1， 并且 将等于
minus 1 so the bit pattern all one is
减去1这样的位模式都是一个是
always a minus 1 in this representation
总是在这种 表示 负 1
I should mention to complement it's not
我应该 提到，以补充它不是
the only way to represent a positive and
只有这样，才能表示正 和
negative numbers but sometimes called
负数，但有时也被称为
signed numbers but it's so Universal
有符号数，但它是如此 普遍
that you'll hardly ever encounter
你会很少 遇到
another case so if you understand two's
另一种情况下，因此，如果您了解二的
complement you have a pretty good
补充你有一个不错的
understanding
理解
of what really is going on
真正是怎么回事
so these numbers I call you max the
所以这些数字我打电话给你最大 的
biggest unsigned number team n the
最大的无符号数队n个
smallest most negative to compliment
最小的最消极的 恭维
lender and team X the largest most
贷款人及 团队x的最大最
positive two's complement this chart
积极补这个图表
shows the range of values for different
示出了用于 不同 的 值 的范围
word sizes or different numbers of bytes
字尺寸或不同 数量的 字节
and so you'll see that with a with an 8
所以 你会看到 一个与8
bit number you only have 256
位数你只有256
possibilities right and so we can either
可能性权，所以我们既可以
choose to think of those as representing
选择作为代表认为那些
the range from 0 to 255 or basically
从0到255 或基本 范围
with two's complement numbers we're just
与补数，我们只是
doing a sort of a wraparound we're
做一个不大不小的环绕我们的
saying well we're going to have half of
说好我们将有一半的
them be negative and the other half will
他们是负的，而另一半会
be either 0 or positive and so it's a
是0或正，所以这是一个
pretty limited range of values of course
当然 值的相当有限范围
and then 16 and believe me back when
然后16，相信我回来的时候
computers had 16-bit word sizes it was a
电脑有16位字长，这是一个
nuisance to keep your numbers within
滋扰内保持你的号码
that range and 32 gives you a pretty
该范围和32给你一个漂亮
decent range it used to be said
体面的范围是用于说
Microsoft had to go to 64-bit word size
微软不得不去64位字长
to represent Bill Gates's net worth but
代表比尔·盖茨的身家，但
for me at least this would easily handle
至少对我来说这很容易处理
my range of normal day-to-day
我正常的一天到一天的范围
transaction so
交易所以
but now with 64-bit at least to us
但现在有64位至少对我们
nowadays those seem like really big
如今那些看起来像真正的大
numbers and hard to imagine exceeding
数字和难以想象超过
the bounds of those so one interesting
这些使一个有趣的界限
feature that you noticed here was I was
功能，你在这里注意到的是我
um like this case here in this case here
嗯这样的情况下，这里在这种情况下在这里
and then this case here of all one I was
再这种情况下，这里都是一个的 我
comparing it to this case here of all
在这里比较本案 全部
one so in other words in both these
一个所以在这两个换句话说
cases and hard to jump boards here
案件在这里很难跳板
you're seeing that you have the same bit
你看到，你 有相同的位
pattern in either case but they the
在这两种情况下的模式，但它们的
numeric they represent different numeric
数字他们代表着不同的数字
values because one is the two's
值，因为一个是二的
complement case and the other is an
补充的情况下，另一种是
unsigned right and you can actually see
未签名的权利，你可以看到
the relation between them is pretty
它们之间的关系是相当
simple because basically what we're
简单，因为 基本上 我们是
doing is we're jumping between a plus
做的是我们加之间跳跃
sixteen and a minus 60 between those and
十六岁， 那些之间 的负 60和
so you'd expect it to change by 32 right
所以你希望它由32 向右 改变
and you see that here that this is 31
你看这里 ，这是31
here and minus 1 this is 22 and minus 10
这里再减去1，这是22 和负10
so they're differ from each other by
所以他们 彼此不同
plus or minus 30 to 2 to the fifth to to
加或减30到2到第五 到至
the word size and so we sort of a long
字的大小，所以我们有点 长
derivation in the book and things here
推导在书上的东西在这里
but that connection is actually fairly
但连接实际上是相当
important because when you jump back and
重要，因为当你跳回来，
forth between unsigned numbers and two's
提出无符号数和二的间
complement numbers in sea
在 海补码
that that's the jump that you get in
那这是你 在 这一跳 得到
other words when of in and so you'll
换句话说在何时，所以你
often find cases where what used to be a
经常发现的情况下曾经被认为是一个
very large number because it was
非常大的 数字，因为 它是
unsigned all of a sudden becomes a
签名突然变成了
negative number because it's considered
负数，因为它被认为是
two's complement so that's what this
补所以这就是这个
next part covers will say that if we
接下来的部分覆盖会说，如果我们
take a cart of 4 bit numbers and we
取4位数字，我们的车
write out all the possible values as
写出所有可能的 值
unsigned or as of two's complement
无符号或 两个补的
numbers then the ones where the low the
数字那么那些在低
higher bit is 0 will be the same in both
更高的比特是 0将是在两个相同的
cases the ones where the higher order
情况下，那些在 高阶
bit is a 1 in this case will differ by
位是1 在这种情况下将由不同
16 2 to the 4th and similarly you'll
16 2到第4，同样你会
notice that these numbers there's a
请注意， 这些数字 有一个
unique it goes unique in both directions
独特的IT是双向的独特
there's a for any given bit pattern
有一个对于任何给定的位模式
there's a unique number it represents
有一个唯一的号码它 代表
and similarly for any number within the
同样地，对于内的任意数量的
given range there's a unique bit pattern
给定范围内有一个独特的位模式
so we can sort of jump between those two
因此，我们可以梳理这 两个 之间的跳跃
and say I can make up a rule for
并说我可以弥补规则
converting between a two's complement
二进制补码之间的转换
number X and an unsigned number UX that
数字X 和一个无符号数 UX说
basically says I'll use the same bit
基本上说，我将使用相同的位
I'll just think of them as being
我只是觉得他们的 作为
different numbers and so and you can go
不同的数字 ，因此，你可以去
either way so for example if we thought
无论哪种方式， 因此，例如，如果我们认为
of this is a a two's complement
这是AA补
representative representation it's minus
代表表示零下
1 this function I'm calling T to you
1这个功能我打电话吨至您
goes from that number minus 1 to this
从数减1变为该
number 31 as the where in between the
如在之间的其中 number 31
two I'm saying they both have the same
二：我说，他们都具有相同的
bit pattern
位模式
and the reason why this rather function
而之所以这样，而功能
that would otherwise seem to have no
否则似乎没有
particular use is important is because
特定用途是很重要的是因为
that's basically what happens in CR
这是在 CR 基本上会发生什么
actually in the program in the program
实际上， 在该程序的程序
on the computer itself has no clue
在计算机上本身没有线索
whether a given bit pattern if it's
是否给定的位模式，如果它是
something you're thinking of as being a
你 作为是一个思考的东西
negative none signed number or tooth
负无符号数或 牙齿
compliment number it's just a bunch of
补码，它只是 一堆
bits to it and similarly we can go back
位， 它 和同样，我们可以回去
and forth between a two's complement and
来回一补之间
unsigned keeping the bit patterns the
无符号保持位模式
same and so I'll call that T to you when
相同的，所以我会打电话 是 t你的时候
I go from signed to unsigned two's
我从符号到无符号 二的去
complement tons unsigned and said well
补充吨无符号和说好
I'll call it u 2t if I go from unsigned
我称之为 ü2T，如果我从无符号去
to signed and as I mentioned the
以签署正如我所提到的
difference for the the numbers where the
对于数字差异的地方
high order bit is a 1 will be by a
高阶位是 1 会由
factor 2 to the W where W is the word
因子2到W其中W 是 字
size of the word and so this can be
字的大小，所以这可能是
thought of as a function where
认为是一个函数，其中
let me just draw it out over here with
让我画出来了 这里
my five bit numbers that is the number
我的五个位数字，是多少
this is to complement again so that was
这是使被再次补充
the number of minus sixteen and then
零下 十六然后是电话号码
there'll be some other negative numbers
还会有一些其他的负数
up to all one this number negative one
直至所有一个这个数字负一
and then I'll have zero and so forth and
然后我会零等，并
then all up to I'm going to run a room
然后一切都取决于我要 运行一个房间
plus fifteen I just draw I got myself in
再加上15 只是我画我自己在
trouble
麻烦
blackboard management is they didn't
黑板管理是他们没有
teach me this cool so I'm going to use
教教我这个凉爽的，所以我打算使用
two boards at once here
在这里一次两个板
Oh what makes it okay we'll make it work
哦， 是什么使得它 没关系 ，我们会让它 工作
so now when we go from the TTU function
所以现在当我们从 TTU 功能 去
then these numbers are going to just
那么这些数字将刚
carry over we'll get zero up through
延续我们会得到 零向上穿过
fifteen but now this number here will
15而现在这个数字将在这里
become positive sixteen and all one will
成为至正十六和所有一次会
become positive thirty-one right and so
成为正面31权等
that's what this picture is showing is
这就是这张照片 是显示 为
it for the pink numbers are the ones
它的粉红色号码是那些
that flip between negative and actually
负居然之间的翻转
the largest of the positive numbers and
最大的正数和
then the green numbers are the ones that
那么绿色的数字是那些
stay the same because they're leading
保持不变，因为 他们领先
bit to zeros
位为零
so why does this matter you never
那么，为什么这件事情 你永远不
thought if you programmed in Python say
觉得如果你在Python编程说
or even Java you don't see that and the
甚至Java中，你看不到 这一点，在
reason is because C is one of the few
原因是因为C是为数不多的
languages where unsigned is actually an
语言，其中无符号实际上是一个是
explicit datatype and you so you can
明确的数据类型和你，让你可以
declare a value being unsigned in it you
声明中也未签名的值你
can if you just say unsigned what you're
可如果你只是说你是无符号是什么
really saying is unsigned int or you can
真正的意思是无符号整数，或者你可以
call something an unsigned care and
调用一些未签名的关怀和
unsigned short or an unsigned long so
无符号短或无符号长，从而
and you're declaring and see that it
和你声明和看到它
should think about using this
应该考虑采用这种
representation we show on the right when
我们代表上显示时的权利
it's working on those numbers so that's
它的工作对这些数字，这样的
sort of one thing and this it's one
排序的一两件事，这个它的一个
thing if you declare a number and use it
的事情，如果你宣布一个数字，用它
that way but what gets people and often
这种 方式，但什么 让人们和经常
got you is if you declare something if
得到了你就是如果你声明的东西，如果
you have a in this case something that's
你有一个在这种情况下，东西是
declared as a to complement number X to
声明为 补充数X
X and you assign it a value you at Y X
X和你为它分配 在 YX 您的值
it will do an implicit casting which is
它会做一个隐式转换是
exactly based on this conversion that
正是基于这种转换是
we've been talking about and vice versa
我们一直在谈论 ， 反之亦然
and so as this example goes through this
所以 作为这个例子中都会经历这个
goes through some examples that if I
经过一些例子，如果我
look at two numbers and I compare them
看两个数字，我对它们进行比较
or I actually I do any operation on them
或者我其实我做他们的任何操作
I add them divide them anything
我加入他们分裂他们什么
implicitly it will try to make these to
含蓄，它会尝试让这些来
be of the same type and the way it will
是同一类型和方式，它 会
do that is to say if both of them are
做到这一点是说，如果两个 都是
signed then I'll do I'll treat them as a
签名，则我会做什么我都会把 它们作为 一个
signed case if either of them is
签署情况下，如果其中一方是
unsigned then I'll convert the other one
无符号的话，我会转换成另一种
to be an unsigned number and do the
是一个无符号数，做
operation and so in particular this set
操作等特别这套
of examples is imagine I'm comparing
的例子是想象我正在比较
these I'm saying these numbers are
这些我说的这些数字是
either equal less or greater
或者等于小于或大于
what will the outcomes be and the key to
会出现什么结果是与关键
answering that question is to first of
在回答这个问题是首先的
all figure
所有人物
out okay is it assigned or an unsigned
出好的是它分配或无符号
comparison should I convert one of these
比较我应该转换其中的一个
numbers to either of these numbers to an
数字到这些数字来的
unsigned form before I do it and the
无符号的形式之前， 我做它 和
rule was if either argument is unsigned
规则是，如果任何一个参数是无符号
then you got to do it and as you see
那么你必须这样做，当你看到
when you put a you at the end either a
当你把一个你在年底或者 是
lowercase u or uppercase u at the end of
小写u或 在年底 大写 ü
a numeric constant you're saying this is
你说一个数字常量，这是
an unsigned value so for example if we
一个无符号的值，因此， 例如，如果我们
compare a 0 and 0 unsigned they're equal
比较0 0 无符号它们相等
and if we combine negative 1 compare
如果我们结合负1比较
negative 1 to 0
负1到0
we'll get that the first one is less
我们会得到第一个是少
because negative 1 is less than 0 but
因为负 1小于 0，但
what would happen with the next one when
将 与 下 一个 的 时候 发生什么
we compare negative 1 to an unsigned 0
我们比较负1无符号0
greater right so this is the surprise
更多的权利，所以这是惊喜
and it has to do with a number that I
并已与多家这样做，我
erased but we can still get it remember
删除，但我们仍然可以把它记
this is negative 1 but when I cast that
这是负1，但是当我投的是
to an unsigned number I'm flipping this
一个无符号数，我这翻
from minus 16 to positive 16 and turning
从零下16至16阳性和车削
this into 31 I'm turning it into
此为31，我把它改成
actually the largest number I can
其实数量最多，我可以
represent and so it will be greater than
声明并因此这将是大于
0 so it's a little bit weird to think
0，所以这是一个有点 有点怪异想
about
关于
I took an unsigned 0 which after all is
我这之后采取了一个无符号0所有IS
to 0 and compared it to negative 1 and
为0， 并且它相对于负1 和
it said oh you really meant 31 didn't
它说，哦，你的真正用意31没
you or whatever word size were using and
您或使用任何字大小和
so it said it's greater and basically
所以说这是更大的， 基本上
the rest of these you can answer in a
其余的这些，你可以在回答
similar way that these two numbers are
类似的方式， 这 两个 数字是
this is clearly one smaller than this
这显然是一个比这更小
no I'm sorry this is a positive this is
不，我很抱歉， 这 是积极的，这是
a negative number
负数
and if I compare those and the positive
而那些 ，如果我比较和 正
will be greater than the negative I'll
将大于 负面 我会
tell you in a minute why this number is
告诉你在一分钟为什么这个数字
written this way the next one it's the
这样写的下一个它的
same pair of numbers but you see it
同样的对数字的，但你看它
flipped and the reason is that this
翻转，原因是这
number on the left is T max 4 so it's
左边数为 T最大4 所以它的
the bit pattern in a 32-bit number
在一个32位的数的位模式
um
UM
to this day I've not memorized this
到今天 我还 没有 这个 记忆
number by the way but and then this
通过但再此路号
number is actually T min
数量实际上为T分钟
and that when I subtract you can think
而当我减去你能想到的
of it as this is negative T max minus
它，因为这是负向 T 最大减
one so that's T min so if I do an
一个所以 这是T最小，所以如果我做了一个
unsigned comparison between those two
这两个之间的无符号的比较
now think of those this leading bit not
现在想起这些的这一领先位不
being a negative weight but a positive
是负的重量，但正
weight you'll see that this is a bigger
体重，你会看到，这是一个更大的
number than this one and so it so it
不止这一个和数量等等，以便它
goes that minus 1 is greater than minus
去那减1大于负更大
2 if they're unsigned because minus 1 is
2，如果他们是无符号的，因为减1
you can think of it as converts into u
你可以把它 作为转换成ü
max it will be the biggest number
最大将是最大的数
possible and minus 2 will be would be 1
可能和减去2将是1
1 1 1 0
1 1 1 0
so that can get fairly confusing one
因此，可以得到相当混乱的一个
final quirk this way of writing this
最终怪癖写本这样
number is there's a little side in the
数字是有一个小 方在
book about it if you write a business
本书，如果你写 商业
number Oh
数哦
as you'd expect - as - blah blah blah
正如你所期望-为 -等等等等等等
six four eight it will actually get the
六四个 IT将 实际获得
C compiler gets kind of confused by that
C编译器得到由那种迷茫
for obscure reasons one other thing I
对于模糊的原因之一，其他的事情我
should point out that it's a property
应该指出的是， 这是一个属性
that I don't think we cover well enough
我不认为我们覆盖不够好
here let me see
这里让我看看
there's a few things that the slides
有几件事， 幻灯片
don't really cover here and I don't know
真的不涵盖在这里 ，我不 知道
why not I like to point out so they're
为什么不是我想指出这样他们
kind of useful properties to keep track
一种有用的特性来跟踪
of is that you notice that if you look
的是，您会发现，如果你看
at the absolute value of T Max and you
在T Max和 您 的绝对值
compare it to the absolute value of T
把它比作 T 的 绝对值
min that it's off by 1 right so that the
分，它由1个右 所以这关
negative number is more negative the
负数是更 负 的
smallest negative number is more
最小的负数更
negative than the largest positive
比 最大 的 正负
number is positive and the reason for
数为正数 的原因
that actually is fairly simple if you
实际上是，如果你很简单
think about it is that the cases where
想想那就是情况
you have zeros includes the number 0
你有零包括数0
you can see it better and there's two to
你可以更好地看到它，有 两
the half year ranges occupied by those
那些占据 了半年 范围
numbers and the negative numbers are all
数和负数 都
negative and there's so the other half
负，有这么另一半
of the range is in there and the point
的范围内的是在有和点
is that you had to use one of these for
是 ，您必须使用下列内容之一
zero and so they're only there's one
零，所以他们只是有一
less one less value left over and that's
少一个少值遗留下来的，这就是
why you end up with this asymmetry and
为什么你结束了这种 不对称性和
this asymmetry is the cause of no end of
这种不对称是没有结束的原因
pain in various ways that like a few the
疼痛，像几个不同的方式
classic example is if you implement
典型的例子是，如果你实现
absolute value
绝对值
like so what do you what does this
像那么，这你是什么
return for team in yeah
返回球队耶
the returns team in we'll talk a little
回报球队，我们将讨论一个 小
bit basically when you try to negate
位基本上当您试图否定
this number that's here you'll end up
这个数字，在这里你会最终
with it back again
它回来了
so it's always a corner case and
所以它总是一个角落情况和
whenever we do program testing we always
每当我们做节目的测试，我们总是
throw that case in there to break things
抛出这种情况下，在有破事
question know that they do that if you
问题知道，他们这样做，如果你
ever look at the in the length and the C
曾经看在长度和 C-
constants they use this as a way of
常量，他们用这个作为的一种方式
representing team in and they do it for
代表队在他们这样做的
that reason because you see it's exactly
这个 原因 是因为你看到它正是
the spot and they put parentheses around
现场他们把周围的括号
it so there's no president's problem but
它所以没有总统的问题，但
you see that number that in six for
你看这个数字，在六 为
seven that team acts and so basically
七个团队 行为 等基本
it's just saying that team n is minus t
它只是说 球队n是减 t
max minus one question
最大减一问题
well- wonderful would get you laughs
良好精彩 会让你笑
yeah mm-hmm yes so comparison is just a
是啊毫米-HMM是 这样的比较仅仅是一个
special case of the more general one
更普遍的一种特殊情况
which is addition subtraction all of
这是加减所有的
those if either argument is unsigned
这些如果任一参数是无符号
then it interprets remaining what is
然后它解释剩下的是什么
being unsigned it it turns out and we'll
未签名它事实证明，我们将
get into this more next time
进入这个更多的下 一次
as far as bit patterns but it turns out
至于位模式，但事实证明
that at the bit level addition
即在该位平 加法
subtraction even multiplication are the
减法甚至乘法是
same whether it's an unsigned number
同样不管它是一个无符号数
two's complement number so what we'll
补号码，以便我们将
talk about that more next time and the
谈论 更多的下一次和
other thing to observe sort of property
另外要观察类的属性
is uh you saw that you Maxis is sort of
是呵，你看到你的Maxis 是有点
like twice Team X plus one right so
像两次X 小组 加一对好
before you max was 15 in our five bit
你之前Max在我们的 五个位 为15
numbers and that's again not too hard to
数字而这 又不是 太难
figure out here's one way to think about
弄清楚这里的思考的一种方式
it t max is a zero followed by a bunch
它t最大是零，接着一串
of ones and if I want to double that
者的，如果 我想一倍
number
数
I basically shift it left by one
我基本上接班接一个离开
position and that would end up with a
位置 ，这将最终 有 一个
zero here so this is UT Max and this is
零这里，所以这是 UT最大，这是
twice team X and now if I add a one to
两次 队X，现在如果我添加一个到
that I'll just set this bit to one and
我将这个位正好被设置为一个
get this so there's various ways you can
得到这个所以有可以各种方式
think about it but that's one way to do
想想但是这是 应该做 的一种方式
it
它
um
UM
it's one other thing that I wanted to
这是我想另一件事
mention too this can get you into a lot
何况这也可以让 你融入了很多
of trouble
麻烦
programming why so let me just show you
节目为何如此让我告诉你
what I mean so imagine I wanted to go
我的意思是这样想象我想去
backwards through an array so I write a
向后通过阵列，所以我写信
loop of the form for I equals n minus 1
形式为我的循环等于n减去1
I is greater than or equal to 0
I是大于或等于 0
I - - and then I do something with array
我- -然后我做什么阵
element a of I i'll just call some
元素的的我，我会只是调用一些
function eyes whatever you want to do in
不管你想要做的功能眼
that loop so that's a pretty standard
该循环 所以这是一个 非常标准
pattern in a loop right except that you
在正确的除非你循环模式
write this greater equal to10
写这个更大的平等到10
you can imagine various uses for that so
你能想象的各种 用途，如此
here's an interesting question what if I
这里有一个有趣的问题，如果 我
were declared as being unsigned
被宣布为未签名
because it's array index after all what
因为它的数组索引 毕竟是什么
will happen with this loop hmm yeah
将这个循环发生嗯呀
what's that
那是什么
yes so the loop will go forever what
是这样的循环将永远走什么
would most likely happen is I would go
最有可能出现的情况是，我会 去
from being 0 to being u Max and that's a
从 为0至是ü最大 ，这是一个
really big number and the Ray you'd uh
真正的大 号码 和你最好的雷 呃
most likely cause a memory fault because
最有可能导致内存故障原因
it's so far out of bounds but the point
这是迄今为止出 界 ，但点
is it wouldn't do what you want it
是它不会做你希望它是什么
wouldn't stop where you want it to and
不会停止，你 想让它和
because of the simple reason that I is
因为原因很简单，我是
of course I is always going to be
当然，我总是将是
greater than or equal to zero because
大于 或等于零，因为
it's an unsigned number so that's uh one
这是一个无符号数，这样的 一个呃
you'd say okay well you should have
你会说没关系，你也 应该 有
figured that one out it can be paired
想通，一 出可以 配对
more subtle though
更微妙的，虽然
if you have something like int I and
如果你碰到这样的INT 和我
then we say something like let me just
那么，我们这样说让我
change it here a little bit so this will
在这里改变它一点点所以这将
be something like this where the I'm
是这样的，其中我
mixing metaphors here I have to confess
这里混合的比喻我不得不承认
but if you use the standard the term
但如果你使用的标准术语
sizeof which is the way you get how many
的sizeof这是你得到多少的方式
bytes it takes to represent some given
字节需要代表某个给定
data type so this will actually be the
数据类型，所以这实际上是
number one so it's not the same loop as
头号所以它是不一样的 环路
before but imagine I'm sort of mixing in
之前，但想象一下，我有点混合
of my arithmetic and making use of some
我的算术和利用的一些
of these built-in forms what would
这些内置的形式会是什么
happen with this loop yeah right
这种循环发生对，没错
yes exactly so sizeof returns an
恰好是这样 的sizeof返回一个
unsigned value it's not actually a
无符号值这实际上不是一个
function it's a built in but it's the
功能它是一个内置的，但它的
result of sizeof is considered to be
的sizeof的结果被认为是
unsigned and so just like I was saying
无符号等等，就像我刚才 说 的
if you have a signed value in an
如果你在一个符号值
unsigned in any kind of arithmetic it'll
无符号在任何种类的算术，它会
turn treat the combination of the two is
转对待二者的结合是
unsigned and so it will actually do an
无符号的，所以它会怎么做的
unsigned comparison here which is almost
这里无符号比较这几乎是
surely not what you wanted and this will
当然不是你想要的 ，这将
just you'll look at this program and you
只是你看这个节目 ， 你
will have any idea why it's crashing
会不会有什么想法，为什么它的崩溃
you'll be so confused and that's the
你会很困惑， 这就是
kind of thing you have to know it's one
这样的事情，你必须知道这是一个
of the quirks of C that probably a fake
C的怪癖，可能是假
could start over again and redesign it
可以重新开始 和重新设计
they'd come up with some different set
他们会拿出一些 不同的 设定
of conventions than they did but
公约的比他们没有 ，但
unfortunately it's way too late for that
不幸的是它是那样太晚了
so this is just one of those things you
所以这只是 其中的一件事情，你
have to remember but yes my point is
要 记住，但对我的观点是
there's some subtleties to spencie
有一些细微之处 spencie
about this business of sign versus
有关此业务的标志 与
unsigned arithmetic
无符号运算
okay so now let's look at a sort of
好吧所以现在让我们来看看一个排序
final class of operations which is
最后一类操作是
suppose I have a number that so many
假设我有一个数字，这么多
bits say eight bits and I want to now
比特说，8 位，我现在想
expand it to be a 16-bit number but it's
扩大这是一个16位的 号码，但它的
a fairly cute rule for doing this
这样做的一个相当可爱的规则
that's called sign extension I'm talking
这就是所谓的符号扩展我说
about two's complement numbers here of
这里大约二补数
how you go take a and make it bigger
如何你去和使它更大
without changing its value and the basic
在不改变其价值和基本
rule is you do it by copying the sign
规则是通过复制的符号做
bit to the left so let me give you the
位向左所以让 我给你
intuition behind that
背后的直觉
so let's look at some 4-bit value well
让我们看看一些 4位值以及
it's pretty straightforward the leading
这是非常简单 的 领先
bit is a 0 I'm just going to do a left
位是0，我只是打算做一个左
shift and then fill in so right wait
移位，然后在这样的权利等待填写
what am I talking about I got ahead of
我究竟在谈论 我的未来
myself I'm talking about something
我自己我说的是什么
totally different
完全不同
no sorry the same number I'm not
没有遗憾相同数量的我 不
changing the number I'm keeping it the
换号我要留着它
same so I just add a zero to the leading
相同的 ，所以我只需添加一个零 到 领先
and this will be the number six still
而这将是老六还
this is plus four plus two equals six
这是加四加二等于6
but now let's think about it as a where
但现在让我们想想它作为一个地方
there's a leading sign bit so this is
有一位为符号位，所以这是
minus 8 plus four plus two is equal to
零下8加四加二等于
minus two so now what look at what
减去两所以现在是什么什么
happens if I copy that sign bit over one
发生，如果我复制 符号位超过一个
position
位置
so this becomes a 1 1 1 1 0 and what
所以这成为1 1 1 1 0 和什么
happens is this is a now has value plus
偏偏就是这是 一个现在已经值 加
8 here but the sign bit has value minus
8在这里，但符号位具有值减
16 and then this is still +2 and +4 and
16，然后这仍然是+2和+4和
so it will still equal minus 2 so here's
所以它仍然会等于减2所以这里的
what happened before my sign bit had a
发生了什么事我的签位了前
weight of minus 8 and my new sign bit
重量减去8 和我的新的符号位
has a weight of minus 16 but I converted
具有减去16的重量，但我转换
that old sign bit into a positive number
旧的符号位为正数
which is plus 8 and those 2 cancelled
其是加8 和 2 的那些 取消
out sit right the duck that you combine
出来坐坐吧， 你 结合 鸭
those two and you get minus 8 which is
这两个，你 会得到减8是
exactly this so you see by sort of
正是这一点，所以你看到 的排序
copying that sign bit over giving it
复制那个标志有点过给它
twice the weight turning it what was the
两次重量把它究竟是什么
sign bit into a positive number you
符号位为正数，你
don't change the net effect of the sum
不改变总和的净效应
and that's exactly the idea of sign
这就是 标志的 确切想法
extension just keep going with that as
扩展只保留作为去
far as you need to carry it over and
只要您需要 携带过来 ，
each time you doing it you're
每次你做 你
effectively doing this business of
切实做好这项业务
coming up with a pair of bits that end
想出 一对 端部 的位
up with the same value is this original
了相同的值就是这个原
bit so that's the idea of sign extension
位，所以这是 符号 扩展 的想法
and you'll see that a lot in bit
你会看到很多位
patterns especially if you see a bit
图案特别是如果你去看了一下
pattern with it starts with a bunch of F
它的图案与一堆的F开始
what that tells you remember f is just
什么， 告诉你还记得 f是刚
for one is a whole bunch of leading one
一个是一个领先的一大堆
that tells you the number is negative
告诉你的数字为负
negative but not too far away from zero
阴性，但不要太远离零
right and and you'll see that over and
右，你会看到过去 ，
over again you'll see bit patterns and
一遍又一遍 ，你会看到位模式和
you just sort of want it when you see
你只是有点想它，当你看到
leading F's you say oh that's a negative
导致F公司，你 说哦，这是一个负
number I know what's going on there and
数 我知道这是怎么回事那里，
so here's some examples but like you can
所以这里的一些例子，但像您可以
see the main idea is you carry that
看到主要的想法是你携带
leading bit from the 16-bit case over
从16位的情况下，对领导位
and make as many copies you need to
让你 需要尽可能多的拷贝
expand the word size and I should
扩大字的大小，我应该
mention with the unsigned case obviously
与未签名的情况下，明显提
you just want to fill in with zeros
你 只是想用零填写
to talk about location and send missing
谈论的位置和发送失踪
slides in this but a final case to look
在这个幻灯片，但最后的 情况看
at is what happens if I make something
在是，如果我做的东西会发生什么
shorter so if I had my unsigned number
所以，如果短，我有我无符号数
from before if this were an unsigned
从之前如果这是一个无符号
number this would be 1 2 8 16 14 17
数，这将是1 2 8 16 14 17
right what if I decided oh I can't
权利，如果我决定哦，我不能
afford for bit I don't have enough money
买得起位我没有足够的钱
for five bits I'm only going to give you
五位我只打算给 你
four well you basically just drop the
四家基本上你刚落
most significant bit and you get eight
最显著位和你达到8
plus two plus one which is a low which
加二加一其为低，这
is nine
是九
and the relation there is that this is
和关系存在，这 是
it's like modular arithmetic
它像模运算
right mod 16 you're taking
右模16 你服用
no thank you
不，谢谢
the risk of improvising so 27 and 11
即兴所以27和11的风险
yeah make cent difference a 16 I knew
是的化妆分差16，我知道
that okay excuse me for my stumbling but
这样行不行原谅我的绊脚石，但
the point being that when you drop this
问题的关键是，当你放弃这一
thing effectively you're just taking the
有效的东西你只是服用
mod some power of two of it like I
MOD的 两个它 的一些权力 就像我
mentioned the case where you're taking
你服用其中提到的情况下，
module eight if you just keep the only
模块8，如果你只是一味地只
the lowest sort of three bits you're
最低排序的三位你
having module eight now one really this
其模块8现在人真正该
is a sort of logical in the unsigned
在无符号排序的逻辑
world your modular arithmetic is
世界的模运算
something that was understood by the
这在过去是被理解
ancient Greek so not too far away from
古希腊 所以不太 远离
human experience but it gets a little
人类的经验 ，但它得到一点点
bit funky if you're dealing with two's
如果你处理的二进制位时髦
complement numbers because this is now
补充的数字，因为这是现在
ten eleven minus five right but this
一〇一一年减五权但这
number if I just drop this bit and call
如果我只是删除此位和电话号码
it a 4-bit number this now becomes minus
这4位数字现在这个变成负
eight two and one
八两，一个
which might have five you say how'd that
这可能有五个你说你怎么 说
happen well actually if you look at it
如果 你看它 还有实际 发生
this is just what you'd get by sign
这 是你的标志得到正是
extension right so this wasn't a very
扩展向右所以这不是一个很
interesting example
有趣的例子
but if we changed it to this then this
但如果我们把它改成这个那么这
would be minus 13 and this would be plus
将减去 13，这将是加
3 and it's a little harder to think
3，这是一个有点困难想
about in terms of modular arithmetic the
关于模运算的方面
way you basically have to think about it
这样，你基本上要考虑一下
is well you know this is minus 13 but
很好，你知道这是负13，但
it's really kind of like 27 and 27 mod
这真的有点像 27 和27 MOD
16 is sort of like or no this isn't 20
16是有点像或没有，这不是 20
we changed our number right so this is
我们改变了我们的权数，所以这是
really kind of like 19 and 19 mod 16 is
真的有点像19 和19国防部16
3 and this is 3 so you can sort of do it
3，这是3，所以你可以排序的做
by coming back around to it but it's not
通过回来解决它，但它不是
some arithmetic property that would jump
会跳一些算术性质
out at you as being something logical
出在你为一些 逻辑
but that happens all the time that and
但是这一切发生的时候，和
it's very common for numbers to get
这是很常见的数字得到
truncated for one reason or another and
截断 或那样的 原因 和
you can see that you can have a negative
你可以看到，你可以有一个负
number become a positive number you can
数字变成正数，你 可以
have a positive number become a negative
也正数变成负
number and all kinds of goofy stuff can
数量和 各种愚蠢的东西能
happen and we'll see funny examples of
发生，我们将看到 的有趣的例子
that when we look at arithmetic so
当我们看到这样的算术
that's that is what I want to cover
这就是 我要盖什么
today and we'll cover the other
今天我们将介绍其他
arithmetic operation on Tuesday so thank
周二所以谢谢运算
you very much
你很